So what do we do?
You need to pass an exam to raise your rank.
And before that, you need to prove yourself.
And so you'll need to take jobs yourself.
But if they know Rentt Faina is
back in town, the guild will...
Rentt, why not register as an
adventurer under another name?
I can't do that! Using two different
names is against the guild rules!
They'll never know.
And even if they do find out,
it won't be a big deal.
Everyone knows Rentt Faina, and they'd have
no end of questions about
how you ended up that way.
But nobody will ask questions
about a wandering adventurer,
no matter how strange they look.
True.
Well, you'll lose what
accomplishments Rentt Faina had,
and you'll have to start over from Iron.
I don't mind.
My goal is...
to become a Mythril-class
adventurer someday. That's all.
Bronze-class
Exam
You already defeated three orcs?
Yes.
Confirm, please.
For a solo adventurer like me,
a magic bag is a necessity.
It took me five years to save up the
money for it, but it was worth it.
They've been dressed properly
and are well-preserved.
I'm sure the client will be satisfied.
So the job's complete, yes?
Yes.
What is it?
Um, can you wait a moment?
That's fine, but...
Hey, did you hear?
He took down three orcs.
Who is that guy?
I've never seen him around here.
I guess as a rookie Iron-class,
I stood out too much.
Here you go.
What's this?
I just spoke to my manager.
Rentt, why don't you try
taking the promotion exam?
Promotion exam?
Yes, the promotion exam for Bronze-class.
It's rare for somebody to get the
opportunity so soon after registering,
but you seem to have the potential.
I'd love to.
So, you've already been asked to
take the promotion exam for Bronze?
Well, it makes sense, with your ability.
It's partially thanks to this body.
Yes, but that just means you're
capable of using its strength.
So, what name did you register
under at the guild?
Rentt Vivie.
You okay?
No, not really.
Why Vivie?
If you use my family name when
everyone knows I was close to you,
people will be suspicious!
It wouldn't be fair to you to have
people thinking you had a weird man
coming and going from your home.
So I decided I'd be your relative.
Well, I guess I can understand that...
But you don't need to worry
about my reputation.
I'm just a broke academic who came here
'cause she couldn't make it in the capital.
I don't care what people think about me.
You've done a lot for me.
I don't want to cause trouble for you.
You've done a lot for me, too.
The cooking, washing, cleaning...
you do almost all of it.
I owe you more than you owe me.
That's not true.
I'm still human because of you.
Rentt...
Then you can just stay
here as long as you like.
You're my relative, aren't you?
Nothing wrong with imposing on family.
Yeah?
I'll take you up on that, then.
Um, who are you?
I'm Rentt Vivie. I'm here for the exam.
Oh, you're him?
Huh? Rentt? I didn't think
you'd be coming today...
I got approved to take the exam.
Yes, but I assumed you'd wait for the
next one so you had time to study.
The next one is several months from now.
But...
Whew, I made it!
He'll lose points for that.
An adventurer who can't show
up on time isn't trustworthy.
Okay, Iron-class adventurers!
We're about to begin the Bronze-class exam!
First, the knowledge test!
We'll test you on guild rules and the
proper handling of monster drops.
You'll have to prove you're
ready to be Bronze-class.
Only those who pass this exam will be
allowed to take the practical portion.
The practical changes each time.
When I did it, it was gathering herbs.
All right, anyone who's taking the
written exam, come with me.
Good luck!
Thanks.
There are more people here than I thought.
Isn't that girl...
Laura!
Right!
I suppose her partner's taking the oral exam.
It's rare for normal people
to be able to read and write.
I learned a lot of things in my village
growing up, like reading, writing,
and knowledge of herbs.
Because I thought I'd need
those to become an adventurer.
So this exam will be easy for me.
It's my second time taking it, too.
Sheesh, why was it so hard?
Don't let it get you down.
You're amazing, Rentt.
I heard you got a perfect score.
That's extremely rare.
I'm just glad I passed.
What will I be doing in the practical?
You'll form a party with a few of the
others and carry out a job for the guild.
A job for the guild, huh?
Ryze! Laura!
You three will be forming a party today.
I'm Ryze Danner, a swordsman.
I use spirit energy to raise
my strength when I fight.
Let me fight in front.
I'm Laura Sati.
I'm a mage, and I can use healing magic.
I'll do my best at the rear.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rentt Vivie.
I fight with a sword, too. I can
use magic and spirit power.
Okay, listen up, everyone!
The practical exam involves completing
a job prepared by the guild.
It will take place at the
Labyrinth of the New Moon.
I will now hand out maps.
Your job is to reach the
point written on your map.
What, so we just have to get here?
You have until sunset!
Dismissed!
Um, are there any restrictions?
None in particular.
You can do anything you like.
Are we all headed for the same spot?
Yes. You're all going to a single location.
The first party to arrive will receive
a reward befitting their efforts.
So it's a race, huh?
It's a race...
Yeah.
Rentt, you ever been to the
Labyrinth of the New Moon?
Yeah.
I see. Me too.
Just partway through
the first floor, though.
That still counts.
I'll be Bronze-class soon, and
then I'll go further down.
Let's hurry.
Yeah.
Wait.
What do you want, Rentt?
We should buy a map.
We can't use the map we were given?
This map is 15 years old.
This old map won't be very reliable.
Damn it! They tried to trick us!
Hey! Rentt?
Can I help you?
I'd like to buy a map.
A map. Of course. That'll be two silvers.
That's expensive!
We can't afford that.
We just need one for the first floor.
That shouldn't cost more
than five bronze pieces.
You've got a deal.
No fooling you, huh, sir?
Sorry.
Is that map really right?
Compare it to the one you got.
Um...
This part had a cave-in?
The path changed at this part, too!
And look! This map has the
location of all the traps, too!
We won't get lost now!
Yeah!
If you want to pass,
kiddos, do what he says.
Not bad, Rentt.
But why would the guild give us bad maps?
Those carriages could've just as
easily taken us to the wrong place.
An adventurer can never
let their guard down.
The point of this exam is to see if you've
got what it takes to be an adventurer.
I see.
Seriously? What a pain.
Remember this.
Remember what?
The guild can be surprisingly mean.
Don't let your guard down because
they're just skeletons.
I know that!
Thanks, Laura!
Sure!
They're pretty good for their age.
They're working together as a team,
and they've each got well-defined roles so
that neither's doing too much for the other.
Are you both okay?
Don't worry about me...
is what I'd like to say.
Were there always this many
monsters around here?
Rentt?
The monsters are being lured here.
Is that possible?
Yeah. You use things like this.
Incense?
What's this doing here?
You'll know soon.
Also, there's an ambush up ahead.
But none of the monsters here should
have that level of intelligence.
Not monsters.
Don't tell me...
That's right. The ones laying
the ambush are human.
But...
We have to fight humans?
Get ready.
I'll take the lead.
Watch out! There are two more!
I told you, I'll take the front!
That's right!
I'll let you handle him, then.
Right.
Wow...
Ryze!
Thanks, Laura!
Damn it! I can't see!
This is payback!
Looks like they don't need my help.
Ryze!
Yeah!
W-We got 'em.
It worked!
They're taking the exam too, aren't they?
Why would they do this?
They wanted to make us fail the exam.
The examiner did say you could do anything.
Right, Rentt?
Anything can happen in the Labyrinth.
The monsters aren't the only threat.
Now you understand, right?
An adventurer can never
let their guard down.
Rentt.
From now on, we'll obey your orders.
Ryze.
Let's keep an eye out as we move on.
Right.
Come pick them up quickly.
He saw me?
Hey, untie me, please.
Oh, sorry.
The man in the mask seemed to
know you were sent by the guild.
Seriously?
Who is he?
I don't know.
Though I can think of one
person it might be...
Maybe my sister was right.
Is there something I can
do for you, Guildmaster?
Relax. Being all formal in front
of me won't earn you a raise.
Yes, I know that.
I heard a strange rumor about the incident.
Rentt Vivie.
The new adventurer you're in charge of.
Has he done something wrong?
Some people are saying he's the criminal.
He showed up out of nowhere
in Maalt. He's quite skilled.
And we don't know anything about his past.
If you want to say that's
suspicious, I agree with you.
But every adventurer has
something in their past.
That doesn't mean we can just
ignore the accusation, however.
If you learn anything,
tell me immediately. Got it?
Yes, sir.
Our destination's just up ahead.
This door... it's what I think it is, right?
Yes.
It's one of several boss
rooms on this floor.
There's no way to get to our destination
except by going through it.
You ever fought a boss?
Not yet.
It's not something two
Iron-classes can handle.
Scared?
Of course not!
There's no shame for an adventurer
in avoiding a fight you can't win.
What, we're not the first?
They think they can beat
us to the goal, huh?
Other examinees?
Good timing.
Good timing?
A party with two kids and
a weirdo in a mask. Great.
We're both taking the same exam.
I don't appreciate being talked to that way.
What, you're lecturing us?
Who do you think you are?
Hey, that girl's actually pretty cute.
Hey, want to come with us instead?
Don't you dare speak to Laura.
Who are you, kid?
We got here first.
Don't get in our way.
What?
H-Hey, it was a joke!
I'm sorry. I don't have
much of a sense of humor.
Look, I'm sorry!
We're not going to try to stop
you from going in first.
Right?
Y-Yeah!
You can go in first.
We're going to rest a little, first.
Okay, we'll take you up on that.
R-Right.
Thanks!
We're lucky they were so dumb!
What are you doing, Rentt?
If they beat us there, we lose!
Why?
Why? It's a race, isn't it?
I'm sure Rentt has a reason, don't you?
So you figured it out, Laura?
You wanted to show us what a
boss fight looks like, first?
That's part of it. But not all.
My leg! My leg!
Those were guild employees, weren't they?
Yes. Even if you lose, you won't die.
Feel better?
Well...
Like I said.
There's no shame for an adventurer
in avoiding a fight you can't win.
Maybe you're right.
But no, that's not what I meant!
If I run away here, I don't
think I'll ever come back.
I'll never be a real adventurer.
Ryze...
So... will you come with me, Laura?
Yeah.
You've made your decision, then.
An adventurer who's been
broken once becomes weak.
Once that happens, it's not rare at all for
adventurers to just quit the job entirely.
Ryze chose not to run because
he sensed that instinctively.
That's an important part of what
it takes to be an adventurer.
Magical Contract